<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on Hugo Cactus Theme</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/tags/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on Hugo Cactus Theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Helpful Plugins for Migrating WordPress from localhost to Production</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2014/03/helpful-plugins-for-migrating-wordpress-from-localhost-to-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2014/03/helpful-plugins-for-migrating-wordpress-from-localhost-to-production/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are some tutorials available for migrating a local instance of WordPress to a live instance for the world to see. In my case, I was ready to deploy some local development to the host, but in my case, I was adding a new custom child theme based on twenty-thirteen (it&amp;#8217;s live at &lt;a href=&#34;http://chocolateandcarrots.com&#34; title=&#34;chocolateandcarrots.com&#34;&gt;chocolateandcarrots.com&lt;/a&gt;). I was pursuing the path of creating a brand new instance of WordPress using a new, clean database, but problems arose when trying to import the content, specifically the post&amp;#8217;s featured image. For some reason, the links would not update, even though everything was on the same server. I&amp;#8217;d like to share some of the plugins I used for a smooth transition from local development to production:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Search and Replace&#34; href=&#34;http://bueltge.de/wp-suchen-und-ersetzen-de-plugin/114/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Search and Replace&lt;/a&gt; by Frank Bultge: This plugin allows to replace strings in the database. I mostly used this when downloading the production database and content (for offline development). I would essentially replace the host url with &amp;#8216;localhost:8888&amp;#8242; (port 8888 since that&amp;#8217;s the default set by MAMP), so all of the content would properly render.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Regenerate Thumbnails&#34; href=&#34;http://www.viper007bond.com/wordpress-plugins/regenerate-thumbnails/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Regenerate Thumbnails&lt;/a&gt; by Viper007Bond: I&amp;#8217;m sure I would have pulled my hair out if I didn&amp;#8217;t find this plugin. Since the website I was working on is image heavy, having a featured post for the blog page was essential. After setting the custom thumbnail size in the WordPress admin area and adding the hook in functions.php, I fired up the plugin and it automagically reproduced thumbnails for my posts. Ahhh!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need to do some WordPress administration for batch jobs, I highly recommend these plugins.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>