<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Canon 50mm F/1.4 on Hugo Cactus Theme</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/canon-50mm-f/1/index.4/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Canon 50mm F/1.4 on Hugo Cactus Theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/canon-50mm-f/1.4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Micro Adjustment on Canon 7D</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/06/micro-adjustment-on-canon-7d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/06/micro-adjustment-on-canon-7d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Until recently, we had a great lens for the 7D: the Canon 50mm f/1.4 USM lens. My wife and I bought this lens with a 7D body to start out our kit. She loves the focal length for her food photography, which you can see over at &lt;a href=&#34;http://chocolateandcarrots.com/blog&#34;&gt;Chocolate &amp;amp; Carrots&lt;/a&gt;. When we first started to use the lens, we were a bit bummed on the sharpness results. Knowing that our camera (along with other professional cameras in Canon&amp;#8217;s lineup) has a lens micro adjustment feature, I decided to give it a spin. Wow, what a difference in sharpness. I set the camera on a tripod a few feet away from the subject (can&amp;#8217;t remember the exposure settings) and snapped a few shots at different adjustment factors. You can search for the details on how this works elsewhere; I just wanted to share the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2012/06/plus5crop.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Before Adjustment&#34; /&gt;
Before adjustment
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2012/06/plus12crop.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;After Adjustment&#34; /&gt;
After adjustment
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there is still some room for improvement, but the increase in sharpness here was enough to appease my wife&amp;#8217;s critical eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that the lens has been dropped on the pavement, it was time to upgrade&amp;#8230; to the f/1.2 version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bottom line: use this feature for every lens that you own. I&amp;#8217;ve also used this feature for the new 50mm and our Tokina 11-16 lens.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>